<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<command name="DRMU" title="Manipulate DataRefs Uncontrolled" group="dataref"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../command.xsd">
    <mnemonic><m>D</m>ata<m>R</m>ef <m>M</m>anipulate <m>U</m>ncontrolled</mnemonic>
    <description>
        Sets datarefs to the requested values, either immediately or progressively over time.
        "Uncontrolled" means that apart from the initial value no feedback will be incorporated into the (intermediate)
        values being set (as compared to a PID controller or similar).
        By not incorporating any feedback, simultaneous manipulation of values may result in noticeably
        (possibly unstable) jumping values.

        Depending on server implementation, datarefs that are owned by the XPRC server may be manipulated asynchronously
        outside X-Plane flight loop phases but generally only if:

        * application is immediate, no timing is requested; i.e. `method=immediate` and `repeatFreq` is not set/single run
        * all datarefs to be manipulated are owned by the same XPRC server instance

        Server implementations are recommended but not required to enable asynchronous manipulation in these cases.
    </description>
    <options>
        <option name="repeatFreq" variableName="X" default="0" defaultRemark="single run only">
            <description>repeat in intervals of X</description>
            <suffixes>
                <suffix name="ms">milliseconds</suffix>
                <suffix name="f">frames</suffix>
            </suffixes>
        </option>
        <!-- TODO: currently no parameter for number of repetitions is specified; add?
        <option name="times" defaultRemark="infinite, until terminated" variableName="n">
            <description>
                number of times to update; command will terminate after `n` retrievals
            </description>
        </option>
        -->
        <option name="method" default="immediate">
            <description>
                how to set the value
            </description>
            <constants>
                <constant name="immediate">
                    immediately set to the requested value (only valid option for blobs)
                </constant>
                <constant name="linear">
                    linear modification from original to requested value
                </constant>
            </constants>
        </option>
        <!-- TODO: currently not implemented (was prepared but commented out - still needed?), marked "under review for removal" in latest pre-XML spec
        <option name="methodFreq" variableName="X" default="1f" defaultRemark="each frame">
            <description>set progressively in intervals of X (no effect if `method` is `immediate`)</description>
            <suffixes>
                <suffix name="ms">milliseconds</suffix>
                <suffix name="f">frames</suffix>
            </suffixes>
        </option>
        -->
        <option name="duration" default="2500ms">
            <description>
                controls the duration of each manipulation cycle, no effect if `method` is `immediate`

                Actual duration depends on flight loop calls (frames in XP).
            </description>
            <suffixes>
                <suffix name="ms">milliseconds</suffix>
                <suffix name="f">frames</suffix>
            </suffixes>
        </option>
        <option name="monitor" default="none">
            <description>
                controls if and which feedback should be sent back to the channel

                Array ranges are based on the requested start index and limited to the length used, only partial arrays
                will be returned for `set` mode. `get` mode may return a shorter actual length (as remaining from the
                requested index) depending on actual dataref content.
            </description>
            <constants>
                <constant name="set">
                    send the currently set value(s) on each update
                </constant>
                <constant name="get">
                    sends what the dataref actually returns after setting on each update
                </constant>
                <constant name="none">
                    only acknowledge command and close channel when done
                </constant>
            </constants>
        </option>
        <option name="phase" defaultRemark="don't care">
            <description>
                when to write the value
            </description>
            <constants>
                <constant name="0">
                    before flight model
                </constant>
                <constant name="1">
                    after flight model
                </constant>
            </constants>
        </option>
    </options>
    <parameters>
        <subparameters multiplicity="+" delimiter=":">
            <parameter>value type</parameter>
            <parameter>name of the requested dataref</parameter>
            <parameter multiplicity="?" condition="optionally, if array or blob">
                `[i]` to set only values from index `i` (`i=0` is the first element; default=`0`)
            </parameter>
            <parameter>
                value(s) to set, encoded as explained in the Dataref Types section

                Array ranges can be written to by only providing a partial array; e.g. addressing index `[4]` on a
                10 item array and passing a value of length `2` will only manipulate indexes 4 and 5 while leaving
                0..3 and 6..9 unchanged.
            </parameter>
            <parameter multiplicity="?">
                value(s) to start from, encoded as explained in the DataRef Types section (optional)

                * If not set, the start value will be read from actual dataref at each start of repetition.
                * Array ranges are handled in the same way as the target value parameter, length has to match.
            </parameter>
        </subparameters>
    </parameters>
    <responses>
        <response>
            status
            * If any dataref cannot be found or any type is unavailable: `ERR`
            * Otherwise: `ACK`
        </response>
        <response>
            Only if `monitor` was requested: intermediate values at referenced time
            * semicolon-separated in same order as requested
            * see dataref type descriptions for value encoding
        </response>
    </responses>
    <notes>
        <note>
            When choosing another `method` than `immediate`, all intermediate values will be calculated relative to the
            time passed since start of command/repetition.
        </note>
        <note>
            Repetition intervals are based on time passed since start of command (no clock skew).
        </note>
        <note>
            If base values are not fixed, they will be read on each first iteration of a repetition. However, the values
            to be set by the same iteration are already calculated with the time passed since calculated start of the
            command/repetition.
        </note>
        <note>
            If base values are fixed, the initial base value is already outdated by the time a new repetition is
            initialized; it will be adjusted according to the time passed since calculated restart.
        </note>
        <note>
            If a repetition interval (`repeatFreq`) is met before the previous cycle’s `duration` concludes, the
            previous cycle's end value will not be set. Instead the new cycle starts applying values seamlessly as per
            the previous note.
        </note>
        <note>
            Datarefs flagged as read-only through X-Plane API may (and will be attempted to) still be written to.
            Internally hosted datarefs (see `DRCI`) are known to be actually restricted and are checked during command
            creation but not afterwards.
            During creation, internally write-protected DataRefs will fail command creation.
        </note>
        <note>
            When accessing internally hosted datarefs (see `DRCI`):

            * Internal availability of datarefs is only checked during command creation.
            * If a dataref becomes unclaimed, the dataref will still be attempted to be accessed through X-Plane
              (the command continues to run).
            * If a dataref becomes claimed (again), the dataref will still be accessed through X-Plane. Write-protected
              datarefs will fail to be written to unless the command is restarted.
        </note>
    </notes>
    <examples>
        <example>
            <client>ABCD DRMU;repeatFreq=5000ms int:some/value:2;float:other/name:3.2</client>
            <server>+ACK ABCD 5412<remark>command stays active and sets both values immediately every 5 seconds until terminated</remark></server>
            <server>ABCD TERM<remark>also stops periodic resets</remark></server>
            <server>-ACK ABCD 15741</server>
        </example>
        <example>
            <client>xyz1 DRMU;method=linear;monitor=set;duration=1000ms int:some/ref:1000</client>
            <server>+ACK xyz1 6402</server>
            <server>+xyz1 6432 102<remark>server sends monitored values as they are being set</remark></server>
            <server>+xyz1 6480 243</server>
            <server>+xyz1 6504 310</server>
            <later />
            <server>+xyz1 7413 987</server>
            <server>-xyz1 7435 1000</server>
            <remark>
                target value (`1000`) has been set after requested `duration` of `1000ms`, channel closed (no repetition)
            </remark>
        </example>
    </examples>
</command>
